<!-- 
  This is part of the Alexandria Manual.
  Copyright (C)  2005  Liam Davison
  Copyright (C)  2007  Cathal Mc Ginley
  See the file alexandria.xml for copying conditions.
-->

<!-- ============= Smart Libraries Subsection ============ -->

<section id="smart-libraries">
  <title>Smart Libraries</title>
  <para>
    The search feature makes it easy to narrow down the view of books
    in a single library according to a single search term. In order to
    support more complex filtering, in a persistent form, &app; uses
    <quote>Smart Libraries</quote>.
  </para>

  <para>
    Smart Libraries are listed beneath the actual libraries in the
    application side pane. They do not actually contain books, but
    rather a set of rules describing which books you wish to see. The
    books from all libraries which satisfy the set of rules will be
    displayed. You cannot directly add books to a Smart Library.
  </para>

  <para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para><xref linkend="new-smart-library"/></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para><xref linkend="edit-smart-library"/></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para><xref linkend="renaming-smart-libraries"/></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para><xref linkend="delete-smart-library"/></para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </para>

  <!-- ======= Creating smart libraries ===== -->
  <section id="new-smart-library">
    <title>Creating a new Smart Library</title>

    <para>
      To create a new Smart library, choose
      <menuchoice><guimenu>Library</guimenu><guimenuitem>New Smart
      Library...</guimenuitem></menuchoice> from the main menu.  The
      New Smart Library dialog allows you to define the rules which
      select which books will be displayed. Each rule is displayed on
      one line. The first drop-down list gives you the choice of what
      attribute of a book you are concerned with (e.g. Title or
      Publisher). The second drop-down gives a choice of conditions
      for that attribute (e.g. contains). Depending on the attribute
      you choose, there may be a text box to enter text or numbers to
      further define the condition. You can add another rule by
      clicking on the <guibutton>+</guibutton> button. You can remove
      any rule (except the last remaining rule) by clicking on the
      <guibutton>-</guibutton> button.
    </para>
    

    <para>
      An example will illustrate the use of Smart Libraries. Let us
      suppose you have a large collections of books by Terry
      Practchett and you add the tag <quote>discworld</quote> to all
      the books in the Discworld series. Let us create a Smart Library
      for all his non-Discworld books.
    </para>
    
    <figure id="new-smart-library-fig">
      <title>A New Smart Library dialog</title>
      <screenshot>
	<mediaobject>
	  <imageobject>
	    <imagedata fileref="figures/smart_libraries_new_smart_library.png" format="PNG"/>
	  </imageobject>
	  <!-- EPS versions of the figures are not required at the moment. -->
	  <!-- 
	       <imageobject>
	       <imagedata fileref="figures/image.eps" format="EPS"/>
	       </imageobject>
	  -->
	  <textobject>
	    <phrase>A New Smart Library dialog showing two rules; The
	    first is <quote>Author</quote> <quote>contains</quote>
	    <quote>Pratchett</quote>, the second is <quote>Tags</quote>
	    <quote>does not contain</quote>
	    <quote>discworld</quote>.</phrase>
	  </textobject>
	</mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    
    <para>
      This is quite simple. We make the first rule select all
      Pratchett books by selecting <quote>Author</quote> and
      <quote>contains</quote> and typing <quote>Pratchett</quote> into
      the text box. Now we click <guibutton>+</guibutton> to add
      another rule. With the second rule we narrow the selection by
      selecting <quote>Tags</quote> and <quote>does not
      contain</quote> and typing <quote>discworld</quote> into the
      text box. Also be sure that <quote>Match <quote>all</quote> the
      following rules</quote> is selected.  When you click
      <guibutton>New</guibutton>, the new Smart Library will be
      created, and you should see the books it contains. You will also
      be able rename the Smart Library immediately, or you can accept
      the default name.
    </para>

    <para>
      Remember, some attributes are boolean - they can either be
      <quote>set</quote> or <quote>not set</quote> (for example the
      <quote>Own</quote> attribute). A text box is not required for
      rules concerning these attributes.
    </para>
  </section>

  <!-- ======= Editing smart libraries ===== -->
  <section id="edit-smart-library">
    <title>Editing a Smart Library</title> 

    <para>
      To edit a Smart Library, select it in the Smart Library list,
      right-click the Smart Library name and select
      <guimenuitem>Properties</guimenuitem> from the pop-up menu. The
      Properties dialog is the same as the New Smart Library dialog;
      you can modify, add and delete rules.
    </para>
  </section>

  <!-- ======= Renaming smart libraries ===== -->
  <section id="renaming-smart-libraries">
    <title>Renaming a Smart Library</title>

    <para>
      To rename a Smart Library, simply click on its name twice in the
      Smart Library pane, and type in the new name. You can also
      right-click on the name, and select
      <guimenuitem>Rename</guimenuitem> from the pop-up menu.
    </para>
  </section>

  <!-- ======= Deleting smart libraries ===== -->
  <section id="delete-smart-library">
    <title>Deleting a Smart Library</title>

    <para>
      To delete a Smart Library, select it in the library pane, either
      right-click and select <guimenuitem>Delete</guimenuitem>, choose
      <menuchoice><guimenu>Edit</guimenu><guimenuitem>Delete</guimenuitem></menuchoice>
      from the main menu, or press the <source>Delete</source> key on
      your keyboard. &app; will ask for confirmation before deleting
    the Smart Library.</para>

    <note>
      <para>
	Deleting a Smart Library does not delete any books, just the
	set of rules by which books are selected for display. However,
	the deletion cannot be undone.
      </para>
    </note>
  </section>

</section>
